REINARD PAGDILAO | SOFTWARE ENGINEER

As a committed and passionate software engineer with a background of BSBA in Economics, I build enjoyable web applications with clean, concise, readable, and scalable code specializing in React (MERN), TypeScript, and Python. With an analytical mindset and experience in a fast-paced high-pressure work environment, I find elegant solutions for complex problems and bring positive experiences to the workplace by being a great interpersonal communicator and taking pride in my reliability. **SKILLS**

Languages - JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, PHP, HTML, CSS | Libraries/Frameworks - React, Next, Express, WordPress Databases - MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Sequelize, Mongoose, ODM, ORM | Other - REST API, OOP proficient

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

May 2021 - PRESENT

My Pet Just Ate - Full-stack application that looks up specific foods and identifies safety for pet consumption

• Implemented MERN (MongoDB, Express.js, React, Node.js) with vanilla CSS3 and integrated Mapbox API for searching animal hospitals near the user, produced in 3-day timeline in collaboration of 2 devs and 3 designers.

Viberant - Full-stack application containing a social meetup aspect allowing users to find, create, and join events

- Implemented MERN (MongoDB, Express.js, React, Node.js) and applied Bootstrap/ Styled-Components for styling frontend in collaboration with 4 designers, one git manager, 2 frontend devs, and a backend dev (myself).
- Contributed by building backend server with built-in API, functional CRUD routes, JSON Web token Authorization, and BCrypt along with helping out frontend devs with building out final prototypes with styling and functionality.

NBA Bite - Full-stack application that retrieves and organizes NBA player statistics from an open-source API

• Implemented RESTful API with Express, PostgreSQL for backend, EJS literals for client-side, and vanilla CSS3 for styling along with data retrieval from Balldontlie API, developed a TypeScript conversion with proper PostgreSQL setup with JavaScript defined types.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Freelance Web Developer | Las Vegas, NV

Nov 2021 - Present

• Built and designed websites on client's preferred platform fitting the needs and expectations of the client, brought positive merchandise revenue, increased visibility on the web, and provide ongoing technical support and updates.

Buffalo Wild Wings - Server | Las Vegas, NV

Aug 2017 - Aug 2021

- Attended a 10+ table section with a range of 2-6 guests per table, often hosting local 10+ persons sports teams. Long standing employment for 3+ years in a 73% annual turnover rate industry.
- Communicated interpersonally while pushing a minimum of \$1000 sales per shift and maintained professionalism in a high demand high volume environment, 300+ guests during peak times.

EDUCATION

General Assembly | Remote

2021

Full-stack software engineering immersive student in an intensive, twelve-week, 450+ hour program focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and team collaboration strategies. Developed a portfolio of individual and group projects. Referred to become a GA Teaching Assistant.

University of Nevada, Las Vegas | Las Vegas, Nevada

2019

Bachelor of Science in Business Administration - BSBA in Economics